

BINH NGUYEN

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



As a Gen Z tech enthusiast with two years of hands-on experience in TypeScript, C#, Python, Java, and Azure Cloud, I began my coding journey right after high school, driven by a fascination with the creative possibilities of software. Initially drawn to art, I found a deeper sense of fulfillment in software development, where crafting algorithms brings both tranquility and purpose.

My personal standards in programming are rigorous, focusing on both the internal and external aspects of every product. I am fully committed to dedicating my heart and soul to each creation.

CONTACT

ducbinhnguyen23@gmail.com

(+358) 417 233 391

• Vaasa, 65100, Finland







CORE SKILLS

- <u>CONCEPTUALS</u>: Object
 Oriented Programming, SOLID
 Principles, Repository Pattern,
 Asynchronous Programming,
 REST, Refactoring, Git, Agile,
 Scrum, UX Design.
- <u>LANGUAGES</u>: C#, Javascript,
 Typescript, Python, Java
- FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES:
 ASP .NET Core, NodeJS, MVC,
 LINQ, XUnit, React, Jest,
 Asp.Net Core, Winform,
 DevExpress, ElectronJS,
 Android, React Native, Pytest,
 Vue3, NextJS, Angular
 (Beginner)
- DATABASES & ORM:
 PostgreSQL, MS SQL Server,
 MongoDB, Entity
 Framework, Dapper, Azure SQL
- <u>DEVOPS & CLOUD</u>: Github
 Action, Docker, Azure DevOps,
 Jira, Kubernetes, Azure Cloud

WORK EXPERIENCES

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER TRAINEE

Integrify | Helsinki, Finland (January 2024 - August 2024) | Remote

Stack: C#, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, React, .NET, Azure Cloud

- Designed and implemented advanced Front-End solutions for the Synchronize Ecommerce Platform, enhancing user experience.
- Led a team of 3 developers in developing robust Back End solutions successfully and integrated an Event Management API with Azure Cloud Services for system reliability and scalability.

THESIS RESEARCHER

ITD Group | Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam (September 2023 - May 2024) | Remote

- Conducted AI script tests for Video Management System.
- Created test reports and onboarding docs, and set up a simulation environment for testing and validation.

STUDENT PARTNER

Pinja Oy | City of Vaasa, Finland (September 2023 - December 2023) | Hybrid Stack: Javascript, Vue3.js, Bryntum library, Azure DevOps

 Designed, developed, and built the Pinja Gantt Chart front-end project, working with Vue3.js under the guidance of Pinja company in the collaboration with 2 other developers.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN

ITD Group | Ho Chi Minh city, Vietnam (January 2023 - August 2023) | Onsite

Stack: C#, Winform, DevExpress, Angular, ElectronJS, Python, Pytest, Numpy, MS SQL Server

- Worked with cross-functional teams of fifteen members
- Gathered feedback for application enhancements, successfully delivering 3 updated versions of the voting counter application.
- Served as an AI API Testing Engineer in a microservice team of 4 software engineers, contributing to test reports and API documentation.

SOFT SKILLS

Googling
Al Prompting
Teamwork
Fast Learning
Design Thinking

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Azure Developer Associate (AZ-204)
Full Stack Open — CI/CD
Full Stack Open — TypeScript
Full Stack Open — React Native
Full Stack Open — GraphQL
Full Stack Open — MERN Stack
Al For Everyone

LANGUAGES

English: Fluent
Vietnamese: Native
Finnish: Beginner (A2)

CO-FOUNDER - CREATIVE MANAGER

Synchronize Recording Studio | Vaasa, Finland (April 2020 - April 2022)

- Collaboration with over thirty industry partners.
- Successfully released twenty eight music products to the market
- Successfully protected over twenty music copyrights.
- Web design, pattern design, brand and label design.
- Worked with advertising platform of Google and meta to reach the targeted audiences.
- Official Youtube channel:
 https://www.youtube.com/@synchronizerecordingstudio6693

RECENT PROJECTS

SYNCHRONIZE ECOMMERCE

TypeScript, React, Tailwind, C#, ASP.NET, PostgreSQL, Azure App Service

- The platform serves as an avenue for selling fashion products associated with Synchronize Recording Studio.
- Collaborated closely with 3 developers throughout the project.
- Deployment URL: https://synchronize-ecommerce-fcsi-7z3b0x6xc.vercel.app
- Front-end repository:
 https://github.com/tripplen23/synchronize-client
- Back-end repository: <u>https://github.com/tripplen23/synchronize-server-</u>

RESEARCHING AND AI API TESTING STRATEGIES FOR VIDEO MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

TypeScript, React, Tailwind, C#, ASP.NET, PostgreSQL, Azure App Service

- Conducted in-depth analysis and coding for the Intelligent Video Management System, directly influencing a 30% reduction in false alarm rates, thereby optimizing resource allocation for security personnel within the organization.
- Public URL of thesis: https://www.theseus.fi/handle/10024/854589

AZURE EVENT MANAGEMENT SYSTEM

C#, .NET, Azure Cloud, Azure Function, Azure Service Bus, Azure Cosmos DB, Azure Application Insight, Azure Blob Storage

- A robust web API for event management using ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework Core, and PostgreSQL.
- Integrated Azure cloud services for seamless storage, monitoring, and performance optimization.
- Project repository: https://github.com/tripplen23/az-eventmanagement





NextJS, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, GroqCloud, Vercel AI SDK

- An AI service for generating bio in different social platform,
- Integrated modern design component by shaden, magicUI, and Vercel V0.
- Optimize prompting for AI models.
- Deploy URL: https://bio-generator-wine.vercel.app/
- Project repository: https://github.com/tripplen23/bio-generator

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

Vaasa University of Applied Sciences (VAMK) | Vaasa, Finland | Graduated in May 2024

FULLSTACK DEVELOPMENT PROGRAM

Integrify Academy | Helsinki, Finland | Graduated in June 2024

